Guide to the Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs ARC.306
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 4: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation photographs, circa 1880s-2002; 43749
  - Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides, 1959-2005; 43884; 8 Linear Feet in thirteen slide boxes and one slide binder
    - Manhattan Historical and Brownstone Stuff, 1971-2001; 44052 (Box 61, Folder 22-24)
      Mostly copy slides of historical images. Some images used in Brownstone calendars. Some slides used in Midtown Manhattan presentation (July 1, 1980), and an index of those slides are available in box 38.
    - Manhattan Historical and Brownstone Stuff, 1971-2001; 44053 (Box 62, Folder 1-14)
    - Manhattan - Miscellaneous, 1969-2000; 44054 (Box 62, Folder 15-17)
    - Naked Ladies of Brooklyn, 1991; 44055 (Box 62, Folder 18-24)
      Photographs of Brooklyn statuary and building ornamentation by John J. Gallagher. Presented by Gallagher at the Montauk Club on October 24, 1991. The photographs were originally taken from 1988-1989 (see Sub-series 4.1: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation prints and negatives). There are four series of numbered slides in the set: One numbered 1-120, which was missing slides 54-55, 108-109, and 111-112; one numbered 181-187; one numbered 37-54, of which the 49th slide was labeled "No Pix"; and one numbered 1-19, which was missing slide 3. Also included were numerous unnumbered slides mixed among some of the numbered sets. It is probable that the numbers on certain slide pages had worn off prior to donation. In addition to the slides, there are prints and negatives of the images available in Box 38.
    - Naked Ladies of Brooklyn, 1991; 44056 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - New York Historical, 1969-2005; 44057 (Box 63, Folder 2-11)
      Mostly copy slides of historical Mahattan images, with a few contemporary Brooklyn building photographs. The first 20 slides were labeled "BRC 2005 Catalogue Dupes."
    - New York Miscellaneous, 1976-1998; 44058 (Box 63, Folder 11-23)
      A mix of copy slides of historical Manhattan images and contemporary Manhattan photographs.
    - Olde New York, 1977-1978; 44059 (Box 63, Folder 24)
      A mix of copy slides of historical images and lecture slides
    - Olde New York, 1977-1988; 44060 (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
    - Park Slope 1, 1967-2000s; 44061 (Box 64, Folder 2-10)
      Includes photographs of the interior of 272 Berkeley Place (2000s). Primarily building exteriors, with some photographs of community activities (Christmas corralling, Montauk Club tour, street fairs).
    - Park Slope 2, 1967-2000; 44062 (Box 64, Folder 10-22)
      Primarily building exteriors, with some photographs of community activities (Christmas corralling, Prospect Park Turkey Trot, Berkeley Place Festival, street fairs).
    - Park Slope Landmarks, 1971-1997; 44063 (Box 64, Folder 22-24)
      A mix of copy slides of historical images and contemporary photographs. See related lecture notes in Box 37.
    - Park Slope Landmarks, 1971-1997; 44064 (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
    - More Park Slope, 1969-1985; 44065 (Box 65, Folder 4-6)
      A mix of copy slides of historical images and contemporary photographs (building exteriors and Berkeley Place Festival /Block Party)
    - Personal, 1959-2000s; 44066 (Box 65, Folder 7-17)
      Includes photographs of vacations, home (272 Berkeley Place), friends, events, and portraits of the Ortners. Photographs of Paris taken by EGO (1982)
    - Personal - Miscellaneous, 1959-2002; 44067 (Box 65, Folder 17-22)
      Consists of photographs of vacations, home (272 Berkeley Place), friends, events, and portraits of the Ortners. Includes 110 Instamatic (12mm x 16mm) slides.
    - Prospect Lefferts Gardens, 1977; 49464 (Volume Slides by Accession # binder, Folder -)
    - Row House Styles - John J. Gallagher, circa 1960s-1990; 44068 (Box 65, Folder 23-24)
      Slides for a lecture presented by John J. Gallagher in 1988. Includes images of Brooklyn building exteriors. Related lecture notes are located in box 38.
    - Row-House Styles - John J. Gallagher, circa 1960s-1990; 44069 (Box 66, Folder 1-7)
    - Row-House photographs - John J. Gallagher, circa 1960s-1991; 44070 (Box 66, Folder 8-21)
    - Socrates Sculpture Park and Shea Stadium, Queens, 1986-1988; 44071 (Box 66, Folder 21-23)
    - Statue of Liberty restoration, 1984; 44078 (Box 67, Folder 13-15)
    - Townhouses Around the World, 1975-2001; 44072 (Box 66, Folder 24)
      Lecture by EHO. See related lecture notes in Box 38.
    - Townhouses Around the World, 1975-2001; 44073 (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
    - Transportation, 1976-1989; 44074 (Box 67, Folder 3-4)
      Mostly copy slides of historic images. Includes subways, ports, railroads, ferries, etc.
    - Victorian Interiors, 1975-circa 1990s; 44075 (Box 67, Folder 4-6)
      Mostly copy slides of historic images. Related lecture notes are located in box 38.
    - U.S. Bicentennial, 1976; 44076 (Box 67, Folder 7-9)
- Series 5: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation lectures, 1970s-2006; 43751; 4.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box, four folders, one oversize folder, three audiocassettes, and one VHS tape
  The series contains files on Brooklyn and historic preservation lectures, dating from the 1970s to 2006. The lectures were primarily delivered by EHO. The files include lecture notes, slide lists, transcripts, clippings, photographs, flyers, audio cassette recordings, and one VHS tape.
  Related slides can be found in Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides.
  Additional lectures delivered by EHO can be found in Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs, Sub-series 3.3: Publicity, and Sub-series 7.2: Brownstone Revival Committee lectures, seminars, and workshops.
  - History and Architecture of Park Slope lecture and slideshow by EGO flyers, circa 1970s-1980s; 49418 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Park Slope lectures and walking tours, 1970s-2000; 43768 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Park Slope Landmarks - History and Architecture lecture notes, circa 1972-1997; 43752 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Related slides available in boxes 64 and 65
  - EHO Urban Land Institute talk, 1973; 43782 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    Includes Brooklyn Union Gas Company, BRC, and portraits of EHO and Fred H.J. Rider
  - Brownstone Style lecture notes, 1973-2000; 43753 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    Related slides available in box 67
  - Lectures and articles (1 of 2), 1975-1993; 43754 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Includes Back to the City Conference and Long Island Historical Society
  - Lectures and articles (2 of 2), 1975-1993; 43755 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Midtown Manhattan lecture slide index, 1980; 43756 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Related slides available in "Manhattan Historical and Brownstone stuff, 1971-2001" file
  - History of Brooklyn at Montauk Club audio cassette, 1981; 44098 (Box 52, Cassette -)
  - Row-House Style lecture by John J. Gallagher slide index and notes, 1985-1988; 43757 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Related slides available in boxes 65 and 66
  - Brooklyn Lecture notes, circa 1988; 43758 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Related slides available in box 56.
  - Naked Ladies of Brooklyn lecture by John J. Gallagher, 1988-1991; 43759 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Held at the Montauk Club on October 24, 1991. Includes flyers and prints/negatives of Brooklyn statuary and building ornamentation. Related slides available in boxes 62 and 63.
  - Brooklyn lecture notes, 1990s; 43760 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Victorian Interiors lecture by EGO notes, circa 1990s; 43761 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - July 4th orations by EHO, 1990-2003; 43762 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Broadway-Flushing Homeowners' Association lecture - EHO, Frank Newton, and Marty Gallant (VHS tape), 1993; 49542 (Box 78, Cassette 5)
    Related ephemera also available in box 78
  - Brownstone Basics #1 lecture, 2000s; 43769 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Related slides available in "Olde New York, 1977-1988" (boxes 63 and 64)
  - Olde New York slide indexes, circa 2000s; 43763 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Related slides available in boxes 63 and 64
  - EHO talks, 2000; 43764 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Fun, Townhouses, Odds and Ends, etc. slide indexes and ephemera, 2000; 43765 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    Related slides available in boxes 59 and 60
  - Brownstone #1 audio cassette, circa 2000; 44096 (Box 52, Cassette -)
  - Brownstone #2 audio cassette, circa 2000; 44097 (Box 52, Cassette -)
  - Townhouses Around the World lecture notes, circa 2001; 43766 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    Related slides available in boxes 66 and 67
  - Brooklyn Nostalgia and Mallification slide indexes, 2004; 43767 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    Precede to Olde New York lecture. Related slides available in box 57.
  - EHO lecture at The General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen, 2005-2006; 43770 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- Series 6: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation general files, circa 1880-2008; 43750; 22.45 Linear Feet in eleven manuscript boxes, five flat boxes, two small boxes, two film canisters, and one oversize folder
  The series contains an assortment of unorganized files that were arranged chronologically by the processing archivist.
  This series is comprised of assorted files relating to Brooklyn (history and culture) and the historic preservation movement that were collected by the Ortners, dating from circa 1880 to 2008. The files include publications, typescripts, correspondence, photographs, posters, 16mm films, VHS tapes, notes, and other materials. It contains a small of amount of historical memorabilia, including an engraving print of the First Methodist Episcopal Church, a Brooklyn Young Republicans ribbon, and a menu from Trommer's restaurant. Architectural drawings for buildings on the south side of Ninth Street (east of Eighth Avenue) in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn are also available in the series.
  The series documents several Brooklyn organizations, including the Park Slope Betterment Committee, Park Slope Block Association, Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM), Brooklyn Museum, Long Island Historical Society/Brooklyn Historical Society (LIHS/BHS), Brownstone Revival Committee/Coalition, Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella projects, and Preservation Volunteers. Of particular note are the files relating to the Park Slope Betterment Committee, which was established in the mid-1960s and was a precursor to the Park Slope Civic Council. The efforts of these groups led to landmarking of the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. Also of note are files relating to the Board of Directors of both BAM and LIHS/BHS.
  The series contains two 16mm films: a WCBS-TV Eye on New York segment titled "So You Want To Own A Brownstone" and a film titled Brooklyn Bridge.
  - First Place Methodist Episcopal Church engraving print, circa 1880; 43784 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Young Republican Club ribbon, 1885; 44083 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Elevation and sections of seven four story and cellar brick houses on the south side of Ninth Street, 237' - 10 1/2" east of Eighth Avenue - Charles Hart, owner and Thomas F. Carroll, architect, circa 1890s; 49408 (Box 75, Folder -)
    Oversize architectural drawings
  - New England Society in Brooklyn, 1904-1911; 43785 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - New York City research (1 of 3), 1911-1980s; 43786 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - New York City research (2 of 3), 1911-1980s; 43788 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - New York City research (3 of 3), 1911-1980s; 44119 (Box 72, Folder -)
    Oversize. Includes "South Brooklyn and Gowanus in History" by Charles M. Higgins.
  - Trommer's menu, 1920s; 43787 (Box 77, Folder -)
    Located at Bushwick Avenue and Conway Street
  - Brooklyn Bridge (Brooklyn Museum), 1958, 1983; 43789 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - "How They Brought Brooklyn Chewing Gum to the Brownstone Ball" typescript by EHO, 1960s; 43790 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Park Slope map, 1960s; 43791 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Prospect Park, 1964-1976; 43792 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Long Island Historical Society - Prospect Park Centennial, 1965; 43793 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Park Slope Civic Council brochure, circa 1965; 49398 (Box 75, Folder -)
  - Park Slope Civic Council releases, 1965-1969; 43794 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    Includes photographs of Frederick W. Richmond
  - Prospect Park Centennial medal, 1966; 44088 (Box 69, Item -)
  - Park Slope Block Association - Preservation, 1966-1967; 43795 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee, 1966-1970; 43796 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee, 1966-1974; 43797 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Flatbush Avenue Improvement Committee, 1966-1974; 43798 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - House Tours (1 of 2), 1966-1986; 43799 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Includes Brooklyn neighborhoods of Park Slope, Carroll Gardens, Fort Greene, Clinton Hill, Prospect Lefferts Gardens, Prospect Heights, and Hoboken, New Jersey.
  - House Tours (2 of 2), 1966-1986; 49469 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Up to the minute map of Grand Army Plaza area the scenic hub and cultural centre of Brooklyn, 1967; 49467 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Bankers Party, 1967-1970; 43800 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee book, 1967-1971; 43801 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - WCBS-TV News Eye on New York - "So You Want To Own A Brownstone" film, 1968; 49536 (Bin 2014.003.06.1, Reel -)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee - Finances, 1968-1969; 43802 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Clipping on the Park Slope North Improvement Project with photographs by EHO, 1969; 49407 (Box 75, Folder -)
  - Landmark Preservation by John S. Pyke Jr., 1969; 43803 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee, 1969-2007; 43804 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Secession, 1969; 43805 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee - Prospect Place project (1 of 2), 1969-1970; 43806 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    Includes photographs documenting brownstones on Prospect Place by James Kalett
  - Park Slope Betterment Committee - Prospect Place project (2 of 2), 1969-1970; 49424 (Box 76, Folder -)
    Photographs documenting brownstones on Prospect Place by James Kalett in an oversize folder.
  - Downtown Brooklyn Development Committee, 1969-1971; 43807 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Brownstone Archival, 1969-1978; 43808 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    Includes Brooklyn Union Gas Company, Cinderella II, Victorian Society in America, Park Slope Betterment Committee, and Brownstone Revival Committee
  - Master Plan - Brownstone Reference, 1969-1982; 43809 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Carroll Gardens architectural preservation poster, circa 1960s-1970s; 49417 (Box 76, Folder -)
    Oversize. In Italian and English.
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) ephemera, 1970s; 43810 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Fort Greene, 1970s; 43811 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn Bridge film (two reels), circa 1970s; 49537 (Reel 2014.003.06.2a,b, Reel -)
  - The Old-House Journal binder, circa 1970s; 49428 (Box 77, Folder -)
  - The Victorian Society in America, 1970s; 43812 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn and Manhattan walking tours (2 folders), 1970s-1980s; 43813 (Box 42, Folder 4-5)
  - Brooklyn history, 1970s-1999; 43814 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Includes Brooklyn Borough President Howard Golden, New York City Mayor David Dinkins, Long Island Historical Society/Brooklyn Historical Society, Battle of Long Island, Civil War, and Gateway National Recreation Area
  - Bedford Stuyvesant Beautification Association - Save Our Magnolia ephemera, 1970; 44106 (Box 72, Folder -)
  - Pasadena, 1970; 43815 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley Place Block Festival poster, circa 1970; 49413 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Swiss article, circa 1970; 43816 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - New York Times letters, 1970-1974; 43817 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Air Conditioning, 1971; 43818 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Brownstone Surveys, 1971; 43819 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Eliot Janeway interview, 1971; 43820 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Historic Park Slope poster, 1971; 49453 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Park Slope rezoning, 1971; 43821 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Wall Street Journal - Park Slope, 1971; 43822 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Brownstone Conference plaques, 1972; 43823 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Brownstone Architecture, 1972-1974; 43824 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM), 1972-2001; 43825 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Boerum Hill, 1973-1977; 43826 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - London - Preservation, 1974; 43827 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Fulton Ferry Brooklyn (South Street Reporter), 1974-1975; 43828 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn history, 1974-1997; 43829 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Brownstone neighborhoods - Jerome Krase, 1975; 43830 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - "By Bernstein" program/poster - The Chelsea Theater Center of Brooklyn (BAM), 1975; 44130 (Box 74, Folder -)
  - Municipal Art Society and NYCOC articles by EHO, 1975, circa 1984; 44108 (Box 72, Folder -)
    Oversize. Includes two typescripts.
  - Long Island Historical Society building report by Lori Zabar, circa 1975; 43831 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Magnolia Tree Earth Center, 1975-1976; 43832 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Grand Army Plaza Quadriga, 1975-1978; 43833 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Includes contact sheet of photographs of the return of statue to the memorial arch
  - Brownstone Course, 1975-1982; 43834 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Long Island Historical Society/Brooklyn Historical Society, 1975-1990; 43835 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    Includes Board of Directors and Library Committee files
  - Bicentennial, 1976; 43880 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Bicentennial Commission - Prison-Ship Martyrs medal, 1976; 44089 (Box 69, Item -)
  - Brooklyn Brownstone Bank, 1976; 43836 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Building the Brooklyn Bridge: The Original Drawings exhibition poster (Whitney Museum of Art, Downtown Branch), 1976; 49470 (Box 76, Folder -)
    Rolled
  - Reprint of Lectures on Ventilation: Being a Course Delivered in the Franklin Institute, Philadelphia during the winter of 1866-67, 1976; 49410 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Battle of Long Island - Bicentennial project, circa 1976; 43837 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Battle of Long Island screenplay, circa 1976; 43838 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Breweries - The Phoenix clipping, 1977; 44107 (Box 72, Folder -)
  - Robert Bidne exhibition poster (FAR Gallery), 1977; 49452 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Cultural ephemera, 1977-1984; 43839 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Includes Montauk Club, Congregation Beth Elohim, Atlantic Antic, Chelsea Theater Center, Henry Street Settlement's New Federal Theater, and Prospect Park Environmental Center
  - If Stoops Could Speak; A History of First Street - First Street Block Association (Park Slope), 1978; 43881 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Old Brooklyn in Early Photographs 1865-1929 exhibition poster (Long Island Historical Society), 1978; 49447 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1978-1984; 43447 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Spencer Mews: adapting an abandoned church for residential and commercial use poster (Preservation Bulletin Number Five), 1979; 49433 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM), 1979-1983; 43840 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Includes program signed by Count Basie
  - Brooklyn Museum ephemera, 1979-1985; 43841 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - City People posters (summer and winter), circa 1970s-1980s; 49432 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Cities are Neighborhoods / Neighborhoods are People / Conserve the Neighborhoods poster, circa 1970s-1980s; 49454 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Triangle Parks Committee - Auction and Art Show posters, circa 1970s-1980s; 49461 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Litchfield Villa and Prospect Park, 1980s; 43842 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Park Slope - Walking tour guide, circa 1980s; 43843 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) ephemera (3 folders), 1980s; 43844 (Box 44, Folder 7-9)
  - Long Island Historical Society - Centennial anniversary celebration, 1980; 43845 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Manhattan Skyline by Tony Graham poster, 1980; 49471 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Preservation: Reusing America's Energy poster (National Trust Historic Preservation), 1980; 49448 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) poster, circa 1981; 49457 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Before the Bridge - American paintings from the Long Island Historical Society poster (Brooklyn Museum), 1982; 49455 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) 120 Benefit report, circa 1982; 43846 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) Local Development Corporation - The Lafayette renovation, 1982-1984; 43847 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1982-1987; 43848 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - "Bird's-Eye View of the Great Suspension Bridge" lithograph poster, circa 1983; 49437 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Centennial (1 of 2), 1983; 43882 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Centennial (2 of 2), 1983; 49397 (Box 75, Folder -)
    Oversize. Includes Nathan's Famous calendar, wacky hat, issue of The Phoenix, and reissue of New York Times issue.
  - Brooklyn Bridge centennial pennants, 1983; 49396 (Box 75, Folder -)
  - Brooklyn Bridge centennial medal, 1983; 44090 (Box 69, Item -)
  - Brooklyn Bridge ceramic dish, circa 1983; 44091 (Box 69, Item -)
  - Views of the Brooklyn Bridge poster, circa 1983; 49459 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brownstone News - Annual Brownstone Fair advertisement in The Phoenix, 1983; 44128 (Box 72, Folder -)
  - Coney Island - Geo clipping, 1983; 43849 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - I Love New York - Brooklyn - Travel Guide poster, circa 1983; 49460 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - "In Transit: Two Centuries of Commuting in Brooklyn" - Long Island Historical Society ephemera, 1983; 49416 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - South Street Seaport poster, 1983; 49431 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Weeksville: Now and Then, 1983; 43850 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Statue of Liberty restoration (2 folders), 1983-1984; 43851 (Box 45, Folder 4-5)
    Includes photographs. Related slides available in box 67.
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden ephemera, 1983-1985; 43852 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn Museum - The Great East River Bridge exhibition, 1983-1985; 43853 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Long Island Historical Society - Name change (2 folders), 1983-1985; 43854 (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
    Includes Architectural and Engineering Museum Planning Study
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1983-1989; 43855 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) - Next Wave Festival program, 1984; 49401 (Box 75, Folder -)
  - Brooklyn's City Hall exhibition poster (Municipal Arts Society), 1984; 49434 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brownstone stuff, 1984-1993; 43856 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Includes clippings, ephemera, and testimony of EHO as Chairman of the Brownstone Revival Committee of New York concerning the Intro. #672 before the City Council (May 17, 1991)
  - From Brooklyn to the Sea: Ships, Seafarers and New York Harbor exhibition poster (Museum of the Borough of Brooklyn, Brooklyn College), 1985; 49462 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Human Proportion - The building of New York's Upper West Side by John J. Gallagher - edited typescript, 1985; 43857 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - New York State Constitutional Bicentennial, 1988; 43858 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - NYC 1898 Consolidation, 1988-1998; 43859 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn Borough Hall Restoration posters, 1989; 49449 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Manhattan Municipal Building Seventy-Fifth Anniversary 1914-1989 poster, 49458 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn clippings, 1990s; 43860 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Clubs - Research by EHO, 1990s; 43861 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - 359 Broadway, 1990s; 43862 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn poster by Warren Linn (The New Yorker parody), circa 1990s; 49456 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Film on Brooklyn: Restoration of Bedford Stuyvesant (VHS tape), circa 1990s; 49538 (Box 78, Cassette 1)
    Existence and Location of Copies